<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ZWaveDevice xmlns="http://www.pepper1.net/zwavedb/xml-schemata/z-wave" schemaVersion="2">

  <descriptorVersion>1</descriptorVersion>

  <deviceData>
            <manufacturerId value="010f"/>
        <productType value="0b00"/>
    <productId value="1001"/>
    <libType value="03"/>
    <protoVersion value="03"/>
    <protoSubVersion value="67"/>
    <appVersion value="24"/>
    <appSubVersion value="24"/>
        <basicClass value="04"/>
            <genericClass value="a1"/>
            <specificClass value="02"/>
        <optional value="true"/>
    <listening value="false"/>
    <routing value="false"/>
        <beamSensor>0</beamSensor>
            <rfFrequency>EU</rfFrequency>
                
      </deviceData>

  <deviceDescription>
                <description>
            <lang xml:lang="en">Flood Sensor</lang>
          </description>
            <wakeupNote>
            <lang xml:lang="en">Wake up interval (battery mode)
Available settings: 0 or 5 - 86399 (in seconds, 5 s. to 24 hours)
Default setting: 4 000 (each 66 minutes)
Defines a time period, in seconds, by which a Flood Sensor will perform a “Wake
up” instruction - communicate with main controller, update parameters, update
software. Flood Sensor will wake up each defined time interval and will always
attempt to connect with the main controller, without retrying if connection fails
(thus preventing a battery from discharging when the Sensor is used at the range
limit, in case of the main controller’s breakdown, or in case the sensor is taken
away from the main controllers range). This parameter is relevant in case of
battery operation - higher Wake up interval means the Sensor communicates less
often saving a battery.
After successful communication attempt, a sensor will go into standby mode,
update parameters or will enter a software update mode.
After failed communication attempt, a sensor will go into standby mode until
another time interval will have elapsed.
Wake Up Interval set to 0 disables sending WAKE UP frame. Device will not
wake up automatically. To wake it up it is needed to manually press the
TMPbutton, which will send Node Info frame.</lang>
          </wakeupNote>
            <inclusionNote>
            <lang xml:lang="en">Triple click TMP button.</lang>
          </inclusionNote>
            <productName>FGFS-101</productName>
            <brandName>Fibaro</brandName>
            <productLine>Fibaro</productLine>
            <productCode>101</productCode>
            <productVersion>24.24</productVersion>
            <batteryType>CR123A</batteryType>
            <batteryCount>1</batteryCount>
            </deviceDescription>

    <commandClasses>
        <commandClass id="0030"/>
        <commandClass id="009c"/>
        <commandClass id="0060" version="3"/>
        <commandClass id="0085" version="2"/>
        <commandClass id="008e" version="2"/>
        <commandClass id="0072"/>
        <commandClass id="0070"/>
        <commandClass id="0086"/>
        <commandClass id="0080"/>
        <commandClass id="0084"/>
        <commandClass id="007a" controlled="true"/>
        <commandClass id="0020" controlled="true"/>
      </commandClasses>
  
    <assocGroups>
        <assocGroup number="3" maxNodes="5">
            <description>
                <lang xml:lang="en">3-rd Association Group reports the device status and allows for assigning single
device only (the main controller by default - the device reports its status to the main
controller).</lang>
              </description>
          </assocGroup>
        <assocGroup number="2" maxNodes="5">
            <description>
                <lang xml:lang="en">2-nd Association Group is assigned to a TMP button and tilt sensor - ALARM
GENERIC control frame will be sent to the associated devices in case a TMP
button is released or a tilt sensor triggered (depending on parameter 74 settings)</lang>
              </description>
          </assocGroup>
        <assocGroup number="1" maxNodes="5">
            <description>
                <lang xml:lang="en">1-st Association Group is assigned to the device status - sending the BASIC SET
(default) or ALARM control frame to the associated devices.</lang>
              </description>
          </assocGroup>
      </assocGroups>
  
    <configParams>
        <configParam number="1" type="constant" size="2" default="0000">
            <name>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Alarm cancellation delay</lang>
              </name>
                  <description>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Delays flood alarm cancelation for the device after flooding has ceased.
Available settings: 0 - 3 600 (in seconds, each 1s)
Determines time period, in seconds, by which a Flood Sensor will retain the flood
state after the flooding itself, has ceased. Sensor will keep on reporting flooding to
the main controller. This parameter settings do not affect acoustic and visual
alarms, which turn off immediately after flooding ceases.</lang>
              </description>
      
          </configParam>
        <configParam number="2" type="constant" size="1" default="03">
            <name>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Acoustic and visual signals On / Off in case of flooding</lang>
              </name>
                  <description>
                <lang xml:lang="en">The parameter allows for LED indicator and acoustic alarm deactivation in case of
flooding detection.
Available settings:
0 - acoustic and visual alarms inactive
1 - acoustic alarm inactive, visual alarm active
2 - acoustic alarm active, visual alarm inactive
3 - acoustic and visual alarms active.
Changes in this parameter settings allow for increasing a battery life. Settings
changes will not affect the Sensors communication with the main controller -
commands to association groups, alarms and reports will still be sent.</lang>
              </description>
      
          </configParam>
        <configParam number="5" type="constant" size="1" default="00">
            <name>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Type of alarm frame sent to 1-st association group (FLOOD)</lang>
              </name>
                  <description>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Available settings:
0 - ALARM WATER command frame
255 - BASIC SET command frame.
The parameter determines a type of command frame sent by the Sensor in case
flooding has been detected or cancelled.
Default setting: 255</lang>
              </description>
      
          </configParam>
        <configParam number="7" type="range" size="1" default="00">
            <name>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Forced dimming level / roller blind opening level, when sending turn on / open command to 1-st association group devices</lang>
              </name>
                  <description>
                <lang xml:lang="en">In case of alarm frames, alarm priority is determined.
Available settings: (1-99) or 255.
The value of 255 allows for turning a device on. In case of a Dimmer it means
turning it on with the last memorized state, e.g. Dimmer set to 30% and turned off,
turned on again using 255 command is turned on with last state i.e. 30%.
Default setting: 255</lang>
              </description>
      
          </configParam>
        <configParam number="9" type="constant" size="1" default="01">
            <name>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Alarm cancelling or turning a device off (Basic) command frame deactivation.</lang>
              </name>
                  <description>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Allows for deactivating device turn off and alarm cancellation functions for the
devices assigned to 1-st association group.
Setting the parameter’s value to 0 results in stopping BASIC SET = 0 or ALARM
WATER = 0 control frames from being sent. After sending flood alarm report the
device will keep on reporting flooding after the flooding itself has ceased. Such a
state can be cancelled by choosing alarm cancelation from the MENU, marked
with green LED colour.
Available settings:
0 - alarm (flooding) cancellation inactive
1 - alarm (flooding) cancellation active</lang>
              </description>
      
          </configParam>
        <configParam number="10" type="range" size="2" default="012c">
            <name>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Temperature measurement interval</lang>
              </name>
                  <description>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Time interval, in seconds, between consecutive temperature measurements done
by built in temperature sensor. New temperature value is reported to the main
controller if it differs from the previously measured by hysteresis (defined in
parameter 12).
Available settings: 1 - 65535 (in seconds).
The parameter determines time interval, in seconds, at which a Flood Sensor
measures and reports ambient temperature and battery level.
If a temperature value will differ from previously reported by a value determined in
parameter 12 (e.g. P12 = 50, i.e. temperatures differ by 0,5°C), new temperature
value will be reported. If a battery level changes, the device will report a battery
status change - Battery Report.
The parameter is relevant when using a Flood Sensor in a battery power mode -
longer time interval means less frequent communication resulting in extended
battery life.
After consecutive FAILED and SUCCESSFUL communication attempts, the
Sensor will go to standby mode.</lang>
              </description>
      
          </configParam>
        <configParam number="12" type="range" size="2" default="0032">
            <name>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Temperature measurement hysteresis</lang>
              </name>
                  <description>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Determines a minimum temperature change value (insensitivity level), resulting in
a temperature report being sent to the main controller, according to the Parameter
10 settings.
Available settings: 1 - 1 000 (each 0,01°C)</lang>
              </description>
      
          </configParam>
        <configParam number="13" type="constant" size="1" default="00">
            <name>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Alarm BROADCAST</lang>
              </name>
                  <description>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Value other than 0 means alarms are sent in BROADCAST mode (with a priority
over other communicates), to all devices within the Fibaro Flood Sensor’s range.
Available settings:
0 - broadcasts inactive
1 - flood (1-st Association Group) broadcast active, tamper (2-nd Association
Group) broadcast inactive
2 - flood broadcast inactive, tamper broadcast active
3 - flood broadcast active, tamper broadcast active</lang>
              </description>
      
          </configParam>
        <configParam number="50" type="range" size="2" default="05dc">
            <name>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Low temperature alarm threshold</lang>
              </name>
                  <description>
                <lang xml:lang="en">The parameter stores a temperature value, below which LED indicator blinks with
a colour determined by a Parameter 61 settings. By default the LED indicator
blinks blue.
Available settings: - 10 000 to +10 000 (each 0,01°C)</lang>
              </description>
      
          </configParam>
        <configParam number="51" type="range" size="2" default="0dac">
            <name>
                <lang xml:lang="en">High temperature alarm threshold</lang>
              </name>
                  <description>
                <lang xml:lang="en">The parameter stores a temperature value, above which LED indicator blinks with
a colour determined by the Parameter 62 settings. By default the LED indicator
blinks red.
Available settings: - 10 000 to +10 000 (each 0,01°C)</lang>
              </description>
      
          </configParam>
        <configParam number="61" type="range" size="4" default="000000ff">
            <name>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Low temperature alarm indicator colour</lang>
              </name>
                  <description>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Parameter stores RGB colour value.
Available settings: 0 - 16777215</lang>
              </description>
      
          </configParam>
        <configParam number="62" type="range" size="4" default="00ff0000">
            <name>
                <lang xml:lang="en">High temperature alarm indicator colour</lang>
              </name>
                  <description>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Parameter stores RGB colour value.
Available settings: 0 - 16777215</lang>
              </description>
      
          </configParam>
        <configParam number="63" type="constant" size="1" default="02">
            <name>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Managing a LED indicator under standard operation</lang>
              </name>
                  <description>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Parameter determines LED indicator’s operation. Set to 0 turns the indicator off,
saving a battery life.
Available settings:
0 - LED indicator doesn’t indicate the temperature
1 - LED indicator indicates the temperature (blink) every Temperature
Measurement Interval (Parameter 10, constant current and battery) or Wake
Up Interval (battery mode)
2 - LED indicator indicates the temperature continuously, only in constant power
mode.</lang>
              </description>
      
          </configParam>
        <configParam number="73" type="range" size="2" default="0000">
            <name>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Temperature measurement compensation</lang>
              </name>
                  <description>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Available settings: -10 000 to +10 000.
Parameter stores a temperature value to be added to or deducted from the current
temperature measured by internal temperature sensor in order to compensate the
difference between air temperature and temperature at the floor level.</lang>
              </description>
      
          </configParam>
        <configParam number="74" type="constant" size="1" default="02">
            <name>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Alarm frame sent to 2-nd Association Group activation</lang>
              </name>
                  <description>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Available settings:
0 - tamper alarms inactive
1 - button tamper alarm active
2 - movement tamper alarm active
3 - button and movement tampers alarm active.
The device is able to turn on alarms resulting from sensor’s vibrations e.g. when
the sensor is moved, or the TMP button released. 2-nd Association Group alarms
are not cancelled.</lang>
              </description>
      
          </configParam>
        <configParam number="75" type="range" size="2" default="0000">
            <name>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Visual and audible alarms duration</lang>
              </name>
                  <description>
                <lang xml:lang="en">The user can silence the Flood Sensor. Because the Sensor’s alarm may last for
a long time, it’s possible to turn off visual and audible alarm signaling to save
battery.
Available settings: 0 - 65535 (each 1 second).
The parameter determines a time period after which alarm will become “quiet” -
still active but the device will go into battery saving mode. Visual or acoustic alarm
will be reactivated after time period specified in the Parameter 76. When alarm
status ceases, alarm will be turned off immediately.
The value of 0 means visual and acoustic alarms are active indefinitely. In battery
power mode the Sensor will never go to sleep which may shorten battery life
significantly.</lang>
              </description>
      
          </configParam>
        <configParam number="76" type="range" size="2" default="0000">
            <name>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Alarm frame / Basic Set frame retransmission time when retaining flood alarm</lang>
              </name>
                  <description>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Parameter determines a time period after which an alarm frame will be retransmitted.
The value of 0 cancels an alarm frame retransmission.
Available settings: 0 - 65535 (each 1 second).</lang>
              </description>
      
          </configParam>
        <configParam number="77" type="constant" size="1" default="00">
            <name>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Flood sensor functionality turned off</lang>
              </name>
                  <description>
                <lang xml:lang="en">Allows for turning of the internal flood sensor. Tamper and built in temperature
sensor will remain active.
Available settings:
0 - Default flood sensor operation (flood detection, reactions)
1 - Built in flood sensor TURNED OFF (doesn’t change its state in the main
controller, doesn’t send Alarms and Basic Set frames with flood state changes.
Always visible in the main controller as turned off)</lang>
              </description>
      
          </configParam>
      </configParams>
  
    <endpoints>
           <endpoint number="2">
            <name>
                <lang xml:lang="en"></lang>
              </name>
                  <description>
                <lang xml:lang="en"></lang>
              </description>
                  <genericClass value="21"/>
                  <specificClass value="01"/>
                  <commandClass id="0031"/>
          </endpoint>
           <endpoint number="1">
            <name>
                <lang xml:lang="en"></lang>
              </name>
                  <description>
                <lang xml:lang="en"></lang>
              </description>
                  <genericClass value="20"/>
                  <specificClass value="01"/>
                  <commandClass id="0030"/>
          </endpoint>
      </endpoints>
    
  
    <resourceLinks>
     
    <deviceImage url="http://www.pepper1.net/zwavedb/uploads/resources/35f1ba94127e0a21ffaddcef49ed06fd3d4ace5d.jpg" />
      </resourceLinks>
    
  </ZWaveDevice>


